truth-it.net 2011-07-23

# Privacy Policy | Truth-It

##  OUR COMMITMENT TO PRIVACY

Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our home page, most internal pages, and on every page where personally identifiable information may be requested.

This notice applies to all information collected from or submitted to the Truth-It! Web sites, but to make this notice easier to read we will use the term "our Web site". Other Truth-It! Web sites may operate under their own privacy notices.

Our Web site contains links and advertisements that link to other Web sites operated by third parties. Truth-It! is not responsible for the privacy practices or policies of such third party web sites and this Notice does not apply to those Web sites.

##  APPLICATION OF THIS NOTICE

This Notice applies only to the information collected by Truth-It! from the users of our Web site. It does not apply to information collected by Truth-It! in any other way, including offline.

##  THE CATEGORIES OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

Our Web site is set up to automatically collect non-personally identifiable information from each visitor to our Web site, via the use of cookies, and coding. It does recognize the home server and possibly the IP address of visitors, but not the email addresses. We can tell which Internet Service Provider our visitors use, but not the names, addresses or other information about our visitors that would allow us to identify the particular visitors to our Web site. This information is used only for internal purposes by our technical support staff.

Our Web site does track certain information about the visits to our Web site. For example, we compile statistics that show the numbers and frequency of visitors to our Web site and its individual pages. These aggregated statistics are used internally to improve our Web site and for product development and marketing purposes generally. These aggregated statistics are also provided externally to advertisers and other third parties, but again, the statistics contain no personal information and cannot be used to gather such information.

In a few areas on our Web site, we ask you to provide information that will enable us to verify whether you are entitled to access and use certain information, materials and services available from our Web site, or to enable us to enhance your site visit, to assist you with customer service or technical support issues, or to follow up with you after your visit, or to otherwise support your relationship with Truth-It!. It is completely optional for you to participate. However, failure to participate may mean that you cannot access and use certain information, materials and services.

For example, we request information from you when you:

  * Log on to certain areas of our Web site, such as the Truth-It! Store, or article discussions where you may be prompted to provide us with your username and password as a condition to gaining access to certain information, materials or services
  * Subscribe to a newsletter, or Daily Truth Fix cell phone text message, or desire to be added to our mailing lists for other products or services
  * Fill out any of our Inquiry Forms, for any reason
  * Participate in a sweepstakes or other promotional offer
  * Provide feedback in an online survey.

In each of the instances above, we typically ask for your name, email address, phone number(s), address, username and password, as well as other similar personal information that is needed to register or subscribe you to services or offers. On occasion, we may ask for additional information to enable us to provide you with access to and use of certain information, materials and services. In the case of newsletters, Daily Truth Fix, or mailing lists, you will be able to "unsubscribe" to these texts and mailings at any time.

##  HOW WE USE INFORMATION: TRUTH-IT! ONLY USES YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION FOR SPECIFIC PURPOSES

The personal information you provide to us when using our Web site, such as your name, postal or email address or telephone number(s) will be kept confidential and used to support your customer relationship with Truth-It!!, and to render our services for you, also to notify you of special offers, updated information and new products and services from Truth-It!, offers from third parties that we think may be of interest to you, or used by Truth-It! or third parties for the purpose of conducting market research or surveys on behalf of Truth-It!. Agents or contractors of Truth-It! who are given access to your personal information will be required to keep the information confidential and not use it for any other purpose than to carry out the services they are performing for Truth-It!.

Truth-It! may enhance or merge your information collected at its Web site with data from third parties for purposes of marketing products or services to you.

With respect to network advertising companies (companies that manage and provide advertising for numerous unrelated companies), to the extent that Truth-It! utilizes such advertising companies to provide advertisements on our Web site, Truth-It! may provide them with your log-in name and any demographic information about you that we collect. Those advertising companies may combine that data with non-personally identifiable data collected by the advertising company from your computer solely for the purpose of delivering on our Web site advertisements that are targeted to you.

Circumstances may arise where we are required to disclose your personal information to third parties for purposes other than to support your customer relationship with Truth-It!, such as in connection with a divestiture or dissolution where we sell all or a portion of the business or assets (including our associated customer lists containing your personal information), or if disclosure is required by law or is pertinent to judicial or governmental investigations or proceedings.

##  YOU CAN OPT OUT OF RECEIVING FURTHER MARKETING FROM TRUTH-IT! AT ANY TIME

We will send you information about our various products and services, or other products and services we feel may be of interest to you. Only Truth-It! (or agents or contractors working on behalf of Truth-It! and under confidentiality agreements) will send you these direct mailings. If you do not want to receive such mailings, simply tell us when you give us your personal information. Or, at any time you can easily opt out of receiving further marketing from Truth-It! by emailing us at marketing {at} truth-it.net.

##  OUR COMMITMENT TO DATA SECURITY

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

##  HOW YOU CAN ACCESS, CORRECT, OR LEARN OF CHANGES TO YOUR INFORMATION

You can request a copy of the personally-identifiable information that Truth-It! has collected about you via the Internet, you can have factual inaccuracies in this information corrected, and you can also verify changes to your information by contacting our Information Privacy Manager at the address below.

##  HOW TO CONTACT US

If you would like to contact us for any reason regarding our privacy practices, please email us at the following address:

Privacy Information Manager - privacy {at} truth-it.net
